{
  "data": [
    {
      "question": "The weather___________ nice yesterday.",
      "a": "were",
      "b": "was",
      "c": "will be",
      "d": "has been",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past:\n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past.\n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...)\n+Subject (the weather) is uncountable, it takes singular verb (was)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Neither he nor they ________ here yesterday.",
      "a": "are",
      "b": "were",
      "c": "is",
      "d": "be",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "- The conjunction or does not conjoin (as and does): when nor or or is used the subject closer to the verb determines the number of the verb. Whether the subject comes before or after the verb doesn't matter; the proximity determines the number.\nEx: Either my father or my brothers are going to sell the house.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "He ________ late for school yesterday morning.",
      "a": "were",
      "b": "are",
      "c": "was",
      "d": "is",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past: \n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past. \n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...) \n- \"To be\" (verb & auxiliary) and subject (in simple past tense) \n+ Was (I, he, she, it, this, that, singular noun/ uncountable noun) \n+ Were (You, we, they, these, those, plural noun/pronoun)\n",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I wish I _____ a doctor.",
      "a": "am",
      "b": "was",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "have been",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "There are three distinct types of  I wish / if only  sentences:\n1/ Wish, wanting change for the present or future with the simple past.\n2/ Regret with the past perfect.\n3/ Complaints with would + verb.\n-Wish + past simple: subject + wish + subject + past simple tense",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "The news on TV last night ________ very good.",
      "a": "was",
      "b": "has",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "be",
      "answer": "1",
      "explain": "- To be very + adjective. \n- 'News' is uncountable noun. \n- \"To be\" (verb & auxiliary) and subject (in simple past tense) \n+ Was (I, he, she, it, this, that, singular noun/ uncountable noun) \n+ Were (You, we, they, these, those, plural",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "I _______ very happy on my last vacation.",
      "a": "am",
      "b": "was",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "will be",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past: \n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past. \n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...) \n- \"To be\" (verb & auxiliary) and subject (in simple past tense) \n+ Was (I, he, she, it, this, that, singular noun/ uncountable noun) \n+ Were (You, we, they, these, those, plural noun/pronoun) ",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "When ________ you born?",
      "a": "be",
      "b": "is",
      "c": "was",
      "d": "were",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "- Passive voice of Simple Past tense: were/was + past participle \n-Subject (you): were",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "Neither of these documents ______ translated into English.",
      "a": "was",
      "b": "need",
      "c": "were",
      "d": "needs",
      "answer": "3",
      "explain": "- Passive vocie: Be (was/were) + past participle\n-The pronouns 'neither' and 'either' are singular and require singular verbs even though they seem to be referring, in a sense, to two things. Ex: Neither of the two traffic lights is working.",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "If Mr. John_________rich, he would travel around the world.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "will be",
      "c": "was",
      "d": "were",
      "answer": "4",
      "explain": "-If clause type 2:\n+The type 2 conditional refers to an unlikely or hypothetical condition and its probable result. These sentences are not based on the actual situation. In type 2 conditional sentences, the time is now or any time and the situation is hypothetical.\n+Form: if + Simple Past, Conditional I (= would + Infinitive)\n+ Verb “to be”: “were” is used instead of “was” (Ex: If I were you, I would….)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    },
    {
      "question": "The weather _____ nice yesterday.",
      "a": "is",
      "b": "was",
      "c": "will be",
      "d": "has been",
      "answer": "2",
      "explain": "-Use the Simple Past:\n+To express the idea that an action started and finished at a specific time in the past.\n+Signal words: yesterday, last week, last year, ago, in (+ period of time in the past), when (when I was young, when I was small...)",
      "category": "1",
      "subcategorylv1": "9",
      "subcategorylv2": "1",
      "type": "1"
    }
  ]
}